A Guide to the Bondurant-Morrison Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #3918
Bondurant-Morrison Family Papers 1787-1936
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
3918
16,000 items
William Harrison
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited to the Library by William G. Harrison, of the University of Virginia, on May 14, 1952.
Scope and Content
This collection consist of ca. 16,000 items, 1787-1936, and contains the papers of the Bondurant family of Buckingham County, Virginia, and the Morrison family of Rockbridge County, Virginia who were related through the marriage of Alexander Joseph Bondurant and Emily MacFarland Morrison in 1859. Alexander J. Bondurant and Emily (Morrison) Bondurant were the chief correspondents in this collection. Alexander J. Bondurant(1836-1910) was a Confederate soldier, farmer, politician, superintendent of Buckingham County, Va. schools, professor of agriculture at Auburn University, and tobacco consultant to the government of Australia. His father, Thomas Moseley Bondurant(1797-1862), was a landowner, member of the board of trustees of Hampden-Sydney College, a soldier in the War of 1812, a member of the Virginia Senate, and one of the founders of the Richmond Whig. His oldest son, Alexander Lee Bondurant(1865-1937) was professor of Latin and head of the graduate school of the University of Mississippi.
Emily MacFarland Morrison(b. 1837) was the daughter of Rev. James Morrison and Frances (Brown) Morrison of Rockbridge County, Va. A copy of her reminiscences can be found in the Rare Books collection (F 231 .B65 1944 1962ed). The Morrison family material consists chiefly of the papers of Rev. James Morrison(1797-1870), including correspondence concerning his family, his congregation, and the Presbyterian Church; also included are his seminary and sermon notes from 1815-1874, and diaries and account books for his home, Bellevue.
Subjects included in this collection are farms in Buckingham Co., Va., family affairs, the Civil War, school administration in Buckingham Co., Auburn University, the University of Virginia, mining and mineral rights in Virginia, immigrant land schemes in Virginia, including the James River Valley Immigrant Society and the Virginia Land and Immigrant Company, Virginia and national politics, tobacco culture in Australia and the southern United States, Rev. James Morrison's education at the University of North Carolina, his pastorates in North Carolina and Virginia, the Presbyterian Church in the South, and the Bellevue School in Rockbridge County, Virginia.
Most of the personal correspondence in the collection is concerned with family matters. A great deal of the letters discussed agriculture with regard to the family farms, especially Variety Shade, and Alexander J. Bondurant's various agricultural positions and interests. AJB's letters from Australia to various family members spanned the period from 1896 to 1901. These contain some information on agriculture and the culture of Australia. Some of the letters from Charles W. Dabney to A.J. Bondurant(1881-1898) discuss iron ore and mineral rights in Virginia as well as agriculture.
The Civil War and its affects is another subject to be found in the correspondence. Letters from Emily (Morrison) Bondurant to Alexander J. Bondurant mention her brothers' war activities and posts (29 Jul, 8 Aug, and 11 Aug 1862; 6 [Apr] and 22 Apr 1863; 1 Mar, 28 Mar, 5 Apr 1865). A 13 May 1863 letter from Thomas Lee Bondurant to A.J.Bondurant mentions the reaction to the death of General Thomas "Stonewall" Jackson. Letters to E.M. Bondurant from A.J. Bondurant mention the war and his desire to support the army (12 Apr, 27 Apr, 26 May 1863). Rev. James Morrison also wrote to his daughter E.M. Bondurant about the war and her brother, Samuel Morrison's appointment as a surgeon in the army (5 Nov 1861, 23 May 1865). Letters to Rev. James Morrison mention the early rumblings of the Civil War and rumors of secession (25 Jul, 20 Oct, 9 Nov, 4 Dec 1860), as well as letters from his sons telling of their posts (20 Feb, 4 Dec 1863; 14 Jan, 21 May 1863).
Politics is also a prominent subject in some of the correspondence. The Bondurants were active in the publishing of the Richmond Whig(est. 1824) and it is mentioned in a few letters. E.M. Bondurant to A.J. Bondurant mentions that George [P. Bondurant](1838-1886) wanted to leave the management of the paper to A.J. Bondurant. Thomas M. Bondurant mentions the paper in a letter (19 Nov 1857) to his son A.J. Bondurant. A letter from George P. Bondurant to his father A.J. Bondurant mentions the Whig again and the Bondurant interests in the paper (22 Mar 1896). Local and national politics is found in several letters from E.M. Bondurant to A.J. Bondurant(26 Jul, 27 Sep, 8, 11, 31 Oct 1896). Letters from Alexander Lee Bondurant to his father A.J. Bondurant mention local politics and the race for the legislature (25 Oct 1887, 7 May 1889). Thomas M. Bondurant was also concerned with local politics; a letter from J.T. Bocock mentions Sen. Flood and local tax collecting practices and the justice system and how they could be changed (8 Jan 1834).
Religion and the Presbyterian Church is also a prominent subject in the correspondence of Rev. James Morrison, pastor of New Providence Presbyterian Church, Rockbridge County, Virginia. The letters from Rev. Elam J. Morrison from Rev. James Morrison(1820-1826) are concerned with family matters, friends in the ministry, questions and and advice about the ministry, the Presbytery and synods. Letters to Rev. James Morrison(1813-1863, n.d.) contain many similar topics and include family letters and letters from friends and relatives in the ministry.
Container List
- Personal Correspondence
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Alexander Lee Bondurant, 1878-1895; (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Alexander Lee and Gabriella (McPheeters) Bondurant, 1896-1909, n.d. (Box Box 1)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Emily (Morrison) Bondurant, 1857-1909, n.d.; (5 folders) (Box Box 1)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from George P. Bondurant, 1889-1909 (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Samuel R. and Sally B. Bondurant, 1891-1898 (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Charles W. Dabney, 1881-1898, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Dabney (Bondurant) and Clifford L. Hare, 1896-1910 (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Lula (Bondurant) and W. Groce Harrison and their children, 1888-1910, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Harriet N. Morrison, 1868-1908, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from Emily M. (Bondurant) and James French Strother, 1879-1902 (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. Bondurant from various relatives, 1854-1910, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous letters to Alexander J. Bondurant, 1852-1919, n.d. (Box Box 2)
  - Letters to Alexander J. and Emily (Morrison) Bondurant, 1880-1910, n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 3)
  - Letters to Alexander Lee Bondurant from Alexander J. Bondurant, 1875-1906, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 3)
  - Letters to Alexander Lee Bondurant from Emily (Morrison) Bondurant, 1866-1910, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 4)
  - Letters to Alexander Lee Bondurant from Related Families, 1886-1893, n.d. (Box Box 4)
  - Letters to Alexander Lee Bondurant from Siblings, 1881-1910, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 4)
  - Letters to Alexander Lee Bondurant from various relatives, 1875-1889, n.d. (Box Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous letters to Alexander Lee Bondurant, 1878-1910, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 5)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Alexander J. Bondurant, 1853-1909, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 5)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant and children from Alexander J. Bondurant, 1896-1899; (2 folders) (Box Box 6)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Alexander Lee Bondurant, 1873-1889 (Box Box 6)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Alexander Lee Bondurant, 1890-1903; (2 folders) (Box Box 7)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Alexander Lee and Gabriella (Means) Bondurant, 1904-1924, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 7)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Fannie Brown Bondurant, 1879-1908, n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Letters to Emily (Morriosn) Bondurant from George P. and Anne (Trueheart) Bondurant, 1890-1912, n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Nannie (Trent) Bondurant, 1882-1890, n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Samuel R. and Sally (B.) Bondurant, 1891-1906, n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Margaret Lavinia (Morrison) Dabney, 1848-1907, n.d. (Box Box 8)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Dabney (Bondurant) and Clifford L. Hare, 1890-1903 (Box Box 8)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Dabney (Bondurant) and Clifford L. Hare and their children, 1904-1912, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 9)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Lula M. (Bondurant) and W. Groce Harrison and their children, 1882-1918, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 9)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Fannie (Brown) Morrison, 1875, n.d. (Box Box 10)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Harriet Newell Morrison, 1854-1889; (4 folders) (Box Box 10)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Harriet Newell Morrison, 1890-1912; (3 folders) (Box Box 11)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Rev. James Morrison, 1855-1865 (Box Box 11)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Mary (Morrison) Smith, 1878-1902, n.d. (Box Box 11)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother, 1880-1891 (Box Box 12)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from Emily M. (Bondurant) and James French Strother, 1893-1903, n.d. (Box Box 12)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from cousins (alphabetical by correspondent), 1852-1917, n.d. (Box Box 12)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from cousins, 1848-1910, n.d. (Box Box 12)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from nieces and nephews (alphabetical by correspondent), 1854-1917, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 12)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from miscellaneous neices and nephews, 1860-1915, n.d. (Box Box 13)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from siblings and/or their spouses, 1852-1910, n.d. (Box Box 13)
  - Letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant from miscellaneous (alphabetical by correspondent), 1857-1910 (Box Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous letters to Emily (Morrison) Bondurant, 1853-1924, n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 13)
  - Letters to Frances Brown Bondurant (Fannie), 1882-1934 (Box Box 14)
  - Letters to George Perkins Bondurant, 1873-1910, n.d. (Box Box 14)
  - Letters to Samuel Rutherford and Sally (B.) Bondurant, 1882-1897, n.d. (Box Box 14)
  - Letters to Thomas Moseley Bondurant, 1834-1859, n.d. (Box Box 14)
  - Letters to the Bondurant family, 1877-1910, n.d. (Box Box 14)
  - Letters to Dabney (Bondurant) Hare, 1889-1903 (Box Box 14)
  - Letters to Dabney (Bondurant) and Clifford L. Hare, 1904-1910, n.d. (Box Box 14)
  - Letters to Lula M. (Bondurant) Harrison, 1883-1893 (Box Box 15)
  - Letters to Lula M. (Bondurant) and W. Groce Harrison, 1894-1936, n.d. (Box Box 15)
  - Letters to Rev. Elam J. Morrison from Rev. James Morrison, 1820-1826 (Box Box 15)
  - Letters to Frances (Brown) Morrison, 1826-1888, n.d. (Box Box 15)
  - Letters to Harriet Newell Morrison, 1847-1912, n.d.; (5 folders) (Box Box 16)
  - Letters to Harriet Newell Morrison and Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother, 1889-1890, n.d. (Box Box 17)
  - Letters to Rev. James Morrison, 1813-1863, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 17)
  - Letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother from Alexander Lee Bondurant, 1885-1902, n.d. (Box Box 18)
  - Letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother from Emily (Morrison) Bondurant, 1881-1906, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 18)
  - Letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother from William P. Hall, 1886-1891 (Box Box 18)
  - Letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother from Lula M. (Bondurant) Harrison, 1881-1902, n.d. (Box Box 18)
  - Letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother from friends, 1884-1901 (Box Box 19)
  - Letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother from various relatives (alphabetical by correspondent), 1879-1903, n.d. (Box Box 19)
  - Letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother from various relatives, 1882-1896, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous letters to Emily M. (Bondurant) Strother, 1880-1903, n.d. (Box Box 19)
  - Letters to James French Strother, 1902-1903 (Box Box 19)
  - Letters to Emily (Harrison) Wilson, 1935-1936, n.d. (Box Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence of the Bondurant, Morrison, and related families, 1816-1910, n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 20)
  - Incomplete letters, ca. 1820-1930 (Box Box 21)
  - Letter fragments, ca. 1820-1930; (3 folders) (Box Box 21)
- Business Papers
  - Business Correspondence of Alexander J. Bondurant Re: Agriculture, 1871-1910, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 22)
  - Business Correspondence of Alexander J. Bondurant Re: His position at the Agricultural Experiment Station, Auburn, Alabama, 1895 Jun-Aug (Box Box 22)
  - Business Correspondence of Alexander J. Bondurant Re: Education, 1885-1909, n.d. (Box Box 23)
  - Business Correspondence of Alexander J. Bondurant Re: Insurance, 1882-1908 (Box Box 23)
  - Business Correspondence of Alexander J. Bondurant from Alexander Moseley, 1870-1877, n.d. (Box Box 23)
  - Business Correspondence of Alexander J. Bondurant, 1850-1889; (3 folders) (Box Box 23)
  - Business Correspondence of Alexander J. Bondurant, 1890-1910, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Business Correspondence, 1825-1903, n.d. (Box Box 24)
  - Financial Papers, 1816-1870's; (5 folders) (Box Box 25)
  - Financial Papers, 1870's-1890's; (5 folders) (Box Box 26)
  - Financial Papers, 1890's-1918, n.d.; (4 folders) (Box Box 27)
  - Legal Papers Re: Insurance, 1869-1906 (Box Box 28)
  - Legal Papers Re: Land, 1780-1909, n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 28)
  - Legal Papers Re: Mineral Rights, 1870-1890, n.d. (Box Box 28)
  - Legal Papers Re: Surveys, Plats, Maps, [1820]-1902, n.d. (Box Box 28)
  - Legal Papers Re: Wills, 1815-1877 (Box Box 29)
  - Legal Papers, 1822-1910, n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 29)
- Papers of Rev. James Morrison
  - Diaries of James Morrison, 1817-1865, n.d. (Box Box 29)
  - Diaries of Harriet Newell Morrison, 1852-1857 (Box Box 29)
  - Essays by James Morrison, 1831, 1856 (Box Box 29)
  - Seminary Notes, ca. 1820's (Box Box 30)
  - Sermon Notes, 1815-1819; (3 folders) (Box Box 30)
  - Sermon Notes, 1820-1826; (5 folders) (Box Box 31)
  - Sermon Notes, 1827-1863, n.d.; (6 folders) (Box Box 32)
  - Sermon Notes, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 33)
- Topical
  - Academic Reports for Bondurant family members, 1853-1899, n.d. (Box Box 33)
  - Agriculture, 1892-1906, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 33)
  - Alexander Lee Bondurant's Latin Exercises from Round Rock Institute, Texas (Box Box 33)
  - Buckingham County Politics, 1844-1896, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Buckingham County Schools Monthly Reports, 1890-1892; (3 folders) (Box Box 34)
  - Education: Miscellaneous papers, 1885-1893, n.d. (Box Box 34)
  - Essays by Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 34)
  - Genealogical Papers, 1859-1896, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - The James River Valley Immigration Society, 1888-1889 (Box Box 35)
  - Lesson Books, 1869-1893, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Lesson Books of Emily (Morrison) Bondurant, 1853-1855 (Box Box 35)
  - Medical diary kept during "Alex's" illness, 1891 (Box Box 35)
  - Memoranda, etc., ca. 1850-1910 (Box Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous, ca. 1870-1920 (Box Box 35)
  - Notices of Deaths and Weddings (Box Box 35)
  - Photographs, 1898-1903, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Political Papers, 1886-1889, n.d. (Box Box 35)
  - Presbyterian Churches, 1839-1901, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Recipes, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Religious essays and miscellaneous papers, ca. 1890's (Box Box 36)
  - Students' papers by family members, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Students' papers, miscellaneous, n.d. (Box Box 36)
  - Students' papers, miscellaneous, n.d.; (3 folders) (Box Box 37)
- Printed
  - Advertisements, ca. 1850-1905; (2 folders) (Box Box 37)
  - Advertisements, ca. 1850-1905 (Box Box 38)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1850-1899 (Box Box 38)
  - Agriculture: Nevada, 1889-1892 (Box Box 38)
  - Agriculture: Virginia, 1835-1910 (Box Box 38)
  - Calling Cards, n.d. (Box Box 38)
  - Education, 1857-1920 (Box Box 38)
  - Education: Alabama Polytechnic Institute, 1885-1895 (Box Box 38)
  - Education: Hampden-Sydney College, 1856-1891 (Box Box 39)
  - Education: University of Virginia, 1857-1904 (Box Box 39)
  - History and Politics: United States, 1888-1910 (Box Box 39)
  - History and Politics: Virginia, 1838-1903 (Box Box 39)
  - Medical, 1870-1909 (Box Box 39)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1887-1910, n.d. (Box Box 39)
  - Organizations, 1856-1909 (Box Box 39)
  - Real Estate Broadsides, 1879-1891 (Box Box 39)
  - Religion, 1871-1911 (Box Box 40)
  - Religion: The Missionary, 1907-1908 (Box Box 40)
  - Religion: Missionary Calendar of Prayer, 1899-1902 (Box Box 40)
  - Religion: Presbyterian Church Publications, 1867, 1887 (Box Box 40)
  - Religion: Sabbath-School Teacher Training Course, 1905 (Box Box 40)
  - Religion: Year Book of Prayer, 1905-1908 (Box Box 40)
  - Travel Data, 1872-1910 (Box Box 40)
- Printed: Books
  - The Adventures of Roderick Random, Vol. I, 1819 (Box Box 40)
  - Frye's Elements of Geography, by Alexis Everett Frye, 1902 (Box Box 40)
  - The Gentleman's New Pocket Farrier... the Horse, by Richard Mason, M.D., 1825 (Box Box 41)
  - House Manual, 1877-1878 (Box Box 41)
  - Inquire Within for Anything You Want to Know, 1859 (Box Box 41)
  - Supplement to the Revised Code of the Laws of Virginia, 1833 (Box Box 41)
  - The School Singer, or Young Choir's Compainion... German Melodies, by William B. Bradbury and C. W. Sanders, 1841 (Box Box 41)
  - A Treatise on Thorough-Bass: or, Harmony Made Easy.. ., by Charles Czerny, [1851] (Box Box 41)
  - The Book of Common Prayer, 1813 (Box Box 41)
  - Holy Bible, containing the Old and New Testaments (incomplete), 1813 (Box Box 41)
  - Holy Bible, containing the Old and New Testaments, 1869 (Box Box 41)
- Bound Volumes
  - Bound Volumes: Accounts
    - Ledger of Robert M. Bondurant, 1816-1818 (Box Box 42)
    - Buckingham County Court Records; Execution Book kept Thomas M. Bondurant., 1824-1828 (Box Box 42)
    - Buckingham County Tax Records kept by Thomas M. Bondurant, 1825-1826 (Box Box 42)
    - Account Book of Thomas M. Bondurant and Accounts of Executors of Thomas M. Bondurant, 1828, 1865-1866 (Box Box 42)
    - Account Book for [Blacksmith] Shop of Robert and Thomas M. Bondurant, 1830-1831 (Box Box 42)
    - Day Book of [Thomas M.] Bondurant, 1834-1839 (Box Box 42)
    - Ledger of Bondurant and Lewis, 1834-1835 (Box Box 43)
    - Day Book of Blacksmith Shop, 1834-1837 (Box Box 43)
    - Day Book of Bondurant and Lewis, 1835 (Box Box 43)
    - Ledger of [Thomas M. Bondurant], 1835-1847 (Box Box 43)
    - Ledger, 1836-1837 (Box Box 43)
    - Farm Ledger kept by Thomas M. Bondurant of Algoma, Variety Shade, Black Rock, and Perry Hill plantations, 1847-1860 (Box Box 44)
    - Account Book of James Morrison, 1857-1859 (Box Box 44)
    - Account Book of Alexander J. Bondurant, executor of Thomas M. Bondurant, 1862-1874 (Box Box 44)
    - Ledger of Alexander J. Bondurant, 1865-1875 (Box Box 44)
    - Plantation Book for "Fish Pond" kept by Alexander J. Bondurant, 1867-1870 (Box Box 45)
    - Ledger, 1868-1869 (Box Box 45)
    - Day Book for "Fish Pond" kept by Alexander J. Bondurant, 1874-1892 (Box Box 45)
    - Record of payments and expenditures kept by James Morrison and Records of Bellevue School kept by Harriet N. Morrison, 1851-1857, 1875-1879 (Box Box 45)
    - Day Book of W.P. [Landeree], 1876 (Box Box 45)
    - "Variety Shade" Inventory kept by [Emily (Morrison) Bondurant], 1879-1883 (Box Box 45)
    - Bellevue School Expenses kept by Harriet N. Morrison, 1880-1885 (Box Box 45)
    - Memorandum Stock Book for "Variety Shade" kept by Alexander J. Bondurant, 1884 (Box Box 45)
    - Farm Day Book and "Time Farm Hands" of Alexander J. Bondurant, 1885-1886 (Box Box 45)
    - House and Farm Ledger kept by Harriet N. Morrison, 1881-1891 (Box Box 46)
    - Day Book and "Time Farm Hand," kept by Alexander J. Bondurant, 1888-1889 (Box Box 46)
    - Farm Day Book of Alexander J. Bondurant, 1889-1890 (Box Box 46)
    - Day Book of Alexander J. Bondurant, 1892 (Box Box 46)
    - Journal of Alexander J. Bondurant (Box Box 46)
    - Partial Index (A-R) [in the hand of Thomas M. Bondurant] (Box Box 46)
  - Bound Volumes: Topical
    - Agriculture Diary kept by Alexander J. Bondurant in Melbourne, Australia, 1899 (Box Box 46)
    - Agriculture Diary kept by Alexander J. Bondurant in Melbourne, Australia, 1901 (Box Box 46)
    - Agriculture Index to State Bulletins, compiled by Alexander J. Bondurant, 1889-1894 (Box Box 46)
    - Agriculture Memorandum of Alexander J. Bondurant, 1892 (Box Box 46)
    - Commonplace Book of Emily (Morrison) Bondurant, 1856-1857 (Box Box 46)
    - Grade Book of Alexander Lee Bondurant and Commonplace Book of Emily (Morrison) Bondurant (Box Box 46)
    - Grade Book, Round Rock Institute, Texas, kept by Alexander Lee Bondurant, 1885-1886 (Box Box 46)
    - List of Buckingham County teachers with professional certificates kept by [Alexander J. Bondurant], 1885-1886 (Box Box 46)
    - Prayer Meeting Notes of Harriet N. Morrison, n.d. (Box Box 47)
    - Recipe Book compiled by/for Marcia Lula (Bondurant) Harrison, 1854-1857 (Box Box 47)
    - Scrapbook of Political Newsclippings, 1816-1852 (Box Box 47)
    - Scrapbook of Printed Sermons, n.d. (Box Box 47)
    - Sermon Notes of Rev. James Morrison, 1847-1848 (Box Box 47)
    - Sermon Notes of Rev. James Morrison, 1853-1859 (Box Box 47)
    - Sermon Notes of James Morrison, and Personal and Church Accounts, 1869-1873 (Box Box 47)
    - Theology Notes, 1843 (Box Box 47)
  - B.V.'s: School Notebooks
    - Chemistry Notebook of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 47)
    - Chemistry Notebook of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 47)
    - Loose Material from Chemistry Notebook of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 47)
    - Chemistry Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant at the University of Virginia, 1888-1889 (Box Box 48)
    - French Notes, n.d. (Box Box 48)
    - French Grammar Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant, 1888-1889 (Box Box 48)
    - French Exercises of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - French Exercises of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - French Idioms Notebook of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - Senior French Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - French Literature Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant at the University of Virginia, 1888-1889 (Box Box 48)
    - French Exercises of William Dinwiddie at University of Virginia, 1887-1888 (Box Box 48)
    - French Exercises of [Alexander Lee Bondurant] at University of Virginia (Box Box 48)
    - German Exercises of Alexander Lee Bondurant at University of Virginia, 1888-1889 (Box Box 48)
    - German Exercises of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - German Exercises of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - German Grammar Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - German Literature Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant at the University of Virginia, 1888-1889 (Box Box 48)
    - Greek Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)
    - Greek Notes of Alexander Lee Bondurant (Box Box 48)